<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Vanilla Expanded - Colonist Voices</name>
  <author>Tempperment 22</author>
  <packageId>colonistvoices.rimworld</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <description>🎤 Bring Your Colony to Life with AI-Generated Voices!

Your colonists will speak with unique, emotionally-driven AI voices based on their personality, mood, current activities, and life events. Every colonist gets their own voice that reacts dynamically to what's happening in their world.

Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IABqrqrV5Qw

⭐ DEMO VERSION - FREE TO TRY ⭐
• 10 FREE speeches per month (no registration required!)
• Full access to all features and voice quality
• Perfect for testing if you love it

💎 How to Get FREE Unlimited Access (Required Reading!)
This mod provides powerful AI voices, but generating speech costs real money. To keep this mod 100% free for everyone, we use a community-pool system.

To get permanent unlimited access, you simply trade one free resource for another:

Get a Free API Key: Go to ElevenLabs, sign up for their free tier, and get your free API key. (This takes about 60 seconds).

Join our Discord: discord.gg/yWC3Arr7pA

Contribute Your Key: Follow the instructions in Discord to contribute your free-tier ElevenLabs key to the community pool.

Receive Your Code: A bot or admin will give you a permanent Supporter Code in return.

Redeem: Go to Mod Options → Colonist Voices and enter your Supporter Code.

You are now a community supporter and have unlimited, permanent access for free! Your contribution helps power the mod for everyone.

✨ FEATURES:
• NO API KEYS NEEDED - Everything handled by our managed backend
• Unique AI voice for each colonist
• Emotionally expressive speech with laughter, sighs, whispers, and more
• Context-aware dialogue based on mood, health, relationships, and activities
• Highly configurable speech frequency and triggers
• Works seamlessly in the background

⚙️ HOW IT WORKS:
1. Install the mod
2. Your first 10 speeches are FREE (no setup required!)
3. Colonists will speak automatically during gameplay
4. Join Discord for unlimited access

🎮 GAMEPLAY:
Colonists react naturally to their world:
• "[excited] This is AMAZING! We actually pulled it off!"
• "[exhausted sigh] Another raid... I can't keep doing this."
• "[whispers urgently] Did you hear that? Something's out there..."

Each speech is generated uniquely based on the colonist's:
• Current thoughts and mood
• Health conditions
• Recent memories
• Relationships with other colonists
• What they're currently doing

🔧 TECHNICAL:
• Powered by OpenAI GPT-4 and ElevenLabs v3
• Centralized backend for optimal performance
• No local API setup required
• Speech history tracking prevents repetition
• Adjustable frequency (max 5% chance per hour)
• Minimum 6-hour cooldown between speeches per colonist

🤝 COMMUNITY:
Join our Discord to:
• Get FREE unlimited access codes
• Share funny colonist quotes
• Request features
• Report issues
• Contribute to development

Discord: discord.gg/yWC3Arr7pA

📝 NOTES:
• First speech may take a few seconds to generate
• Internet connection required
• Demo quota resets monthly (1st of each month)
• Supporter status is permanent once redeemed

⚠️ REQUIREMENTS:
• RimWorld 1.6
• Harmony (auto-downloads from Steam Workshop)
• Active internet connection

This default is a DEMO version with limited free speeches. However full unlimited access is available FREE to all community supporters!

If you want a version that doesnt use my servers as a backend you can use this version here https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3599437545

Note: This mod is in no way affiliated with the creator and mods of the OG Vanilla Expanded mod series.</description>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <url>https://discord.gg/yWC3Arr7pA</url>
</ModMetaData>
